<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog.atom"/>
  <title>MrandMrsMuscle - Blog</title>
  <updated>2019-09-11T08:17:00+04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MrandMrsMuscle</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/3-natural-fat-burners-for-beginners</id>
    <published>2019-09-11T08:17:00+04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-11T08:17:24+04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/3-natural-fat-burners-for-beginners"/>
    <title>3 Natural Fat Burners for Beginners</title>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Addo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Natural Fat Burners are nutritional supplements that focus on promoting fat loss via </span><span>a series of methods. These include; boosting energy expenditure, thermogenesis, impairing fat absorption, increasing fat oxidation and suppressing appetite.</span></p>
<p><span>Click <strong>Read More</strong> to find out if Fat Burners are suitable for you and which ones to take.</span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/3-natural-fat-burners-for-beginners">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="natural fat burner green tea" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0114/8164/5152/files/green_tea_extract_natural_fat_burner_1024x1024.jpg?v=1568172348" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Almost everyone on their journey to weight loss arrives at a point where they want faster results. More often than not they immediately start searching high and low for a '<strong>MAGIC</strong>' fat loss pill, powder or special medicine that will help them get there. So, we intend to make your search a little less daunting and give you a quick insight as to what you might need.</p>
<p>Natural Fat Burners are nutritional supplements that focus on promoting fat loss via a series of methods. These include; boosting energy expenditure, thermogenesis, impairing fat absorption, increasing fat oxidation and suppressing appetite (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21951331">1</a>).</p>
<p>However, it is very important to note that no matter how fast we want results there is no ‘Magic Pill’ that will wipe the kilos of fat away from your body without you having to lift a finger!</p>
<p>You have to put in the work, get your heart rate up and focus on building muscle. The higher your heart rate is during exercise the more active calories your burn. The more muscle you build during exercise the more calories burn at rest.</p>
<p>Here is our compiled list.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;">3 Natural Fat Burners Perfect for Beginners</span></h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Green Tea Extract</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Green Tea Extract is a concentrated form of green tea that can be ingested as a capsule or powder. It contains caffeine and an active compound called EGCG (Epigallocatechin Gallate) which assists in fat burning by inducing ‘Thermogenesis’ - a metabolic process in which the body burns calories to produce heat (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17201629">2</a>).</p>
<p>A multi-study comparing green tea extract to a placebo showed that taking green tea extract in combination with caffeine significantly boosted energy expenditure by 4.7% and increased fat burning by 16% over a 24 hour period (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21366839/">3</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Caffeine</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Who doesn’t love a bit of caffeine first thing in the morning?! This POWERFUL stimulant is the main active ingredient in Coffee (liquid gold for the millions of us dependent on it to get into the office) and can be found in both green tea and cocoa beans. It is also one of the most common ingredients in synthetic/ commercial fat burners.</p>
<p>Studies have shown caffeine to significantly boost your metabolism and fat burning by around 16% over a 2-3hour period after ingestion (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/7369170">4</a>). This makes caffeine a great option pre-workout or just before a meal.</p>
<p>You can get caffeine as a pill, powder or from drinking strong cups of coffee.</p>
<p>Note: Regular consumption of caffeine at high levels can make you tolerant to its effects.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Protein</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Is protein really a fat burner? Not quite. However, when we look at the thermic effect of food (the number of calories used to digest food) protein is the winner. For example, 25 grams of protein takes 3-4 times more energy to digest than 25 grams of carbs and up to 10 times more energy to digest than fat.</p>
<p>In addition, a high protein intake can help you reduce body fat by increasing satiety, reducing appetite hormones like ghrelin, preserving muscle mass and boosting your metabolism (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4258944/">5</a>).</p>
<p><strong>BONUS: VEGAN Fat Burner Capsules</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://womens.best/mrandmrsmuscle" target="_blank" title="Womens Best Burner Capsules" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img alt="womens best fat burner" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0114/8164/5152/files/womens_best_burner_caps_medium.jpg?v=1568175349" style="float: none;"></a></p>
<p>Women's Best have <span>developed a <strong>VEGAN </strong>power-formula that helps to burn fat as well as provide an extra energy boost! Supported and approved by the EFSA (European Food and Safety Authority) it contains the ingredient choline, which contributes to a normal fat metabolism.</span><br><br><span>The combination also includes; Green Tea Extract, </span><span class="morecontent0"><span>Caffeine, vitamin B12, biotin and vitamin B7 (help with tiredness and fatigue and support stable fat metabolism).</span></span></p>
<p><a href="https://womens.best/mrandmrsmuscle" target="_blank" title="Women's Best Supplement Store" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="morecontent0"><span>Click here to see the product in greater detail and if it is suitable for you.</span></span></a></p>
<p> </p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;">Bottom Line</span></h2>
<p>It is easy to become discouraged or want faster results when you feel that you are giving it your all. However, opting for Fat Burners isn’t the complete solution! For Fat Burners to work efficiently they must be taken with a proper nutrition and exercise regime already in place.</p>
<p><a href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/collections/all" target="_blank" title="MrandMrsMuscle Workout Calendars" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Are you using our workout calendars? - Click here to get your program</em></a></p>
<p>The supplements we have listed above are a great place to start. They have been thoroughly researched and backed by numerous studies. If you are finding that you are putting in maximal effort but the fat or weight is not shifting, then there is a good chance that your nutrition is incorrect, you are suffering with a few hormonal imbalances or you simply aren’t exercising enough.</p>
<p>Pace your weight loss journey, tick all the right boxes and research, research, research.</p>
<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script><ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display: block; text-align: center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4628548607785108" data-ad-slot="6535981438"></ins><script>// <![CDATA[
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/what-is-best-for-fat-loss-cardio-hiit-or-weight-training</id>
    <published>2019-09-09T18:59:00+04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-09T19:39:40+04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/what-is-best-for-fat-loss-cardio-hiit-or-weight-training"/>
    <title>What is best for Fat Loss - Cardio, HIIT or Weight Training?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Addo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Fat loss is one of the most common fitness goals today. Almost, everyone is looking for a slimmer waist, muscular definition and the self-confidence that comes as a reward of achieving these goals through hard work.</span></p>
<p><span>So what is the best way to get there?<br>Click on read more to find out.</span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/what-is-best-for-fat-loss-cardio-hiit-or-weight-training">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="what exercise is best for fat loss" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0114/8164/5152/files/what_is_exercise_is_best_for_fat_loss_1024x1024.jpg?v=1568041056" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Fat loss is one of the most common fitness goals today. Almost, everyone is looking for a slimmer waist, muscular definition and the self-confidence that comes as a reward of achieving these goals through hard work. </p>
<p>However, a majority of aspiring gym-goers and home fitness addicts are conflicted as to how to get there due to a wealth of information from all directions.</p>
<p>A common question that we get in our inbox is “Which type of exercise is best for fat loss?”, actually the question is more like “Which type of exercise is going to give me 11 line abs?!”</p>
<p>The hard truth is that there is no singular fat burning exercise or specific exercise that is going to give you 11 line abs. Instead you will need to combine a series of exercises and follow a well structured exercise and nutrition program.</p>
<p>This article is going to give you a quick rundown of the most popular training types: cardio, hiit and weight training and how they attribute towards your fat loss.</p>
<h1><span style="color: #3d85c6;"><strong>Cardio</strong> </span></h1>
<p>Cardio training is easy to perform and has multiple noteworthy benefits, these include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reduced stress levels</li>
<li>Increased bone density</li>
<li>Better circulation</li>
<li>Stronger heart and lungs</li>
<li>Increased energy over time</li>
<li>Improved sleep quality</li>
<li>Helps to control blood sugar levels</li>
<li>Weight loss</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, extensive research has shown that during a training session cardio burns more calories than weight training minute for minute, and the more you weigh the more calories you burn.</p>
<p>Furthermore, cardio can be performed by doing almost anything that requires you to move. For example; dancing, walking, power walking, jogging, cycling, roller-skating, skipping, kicking a football in the park, chasing baby around the house, you name it!</p>
<p>Cardio is fun, has a low barrier to entry and is a great starting point for any individual looking to begin a fitness regime.</p>
<p>However, cardio training also comes with its challenges. Burning more calories during your session is great, but what about when the session is over?</p>
<p>Cardio uses almost of your muscles but does very little to shock them or stress them into growth. With cardio training there is also very little Excess Post-Exercise Oxygen Consumption (EPOC) also known as ‘After-burn’.</p>
<p>After-burn is an increased rate of oxygen intake following strenuous activity, it is this that leads to greater fat loss. However, steady state cardio is considered low impact and therefore the low level of EPOC means that you only burn significant calories when you are doing the exercise.</p>
<p>This is where HIIT comes in.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;">High Intensity Interval Training (HIIT)</span></h2>
<p>HIIT training is essentially another form of cardio. It involves short bursts of very intense exercise combined with low intensity recovery periods. Research has shown HIIT to burn more calories per minute than steady state cardio (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24552392">1</a>). In addition, it drives up your oxygen intake capacity and ramps up your metabolism allowing you to burn calories long after your session is over.</p>
<p>Furthermore, HIIT improves both your anaerobic (intensity, muscle building) and aerobic (cardiovascular, oxygen consuming) body systems.</p>
<p>This means with HIIT you can build muscle and burn fat. The more muscle you have, the more calories you burn lugging it around! </p>
<p>It is one of the reasons why we absolutely love it.</p>
<p><a href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/collections/frontpage/" title="MrandMrsMuscle Workout Calendars">Click here to download our HIIT Workout Calendar for this month!</a></p>
<h2>
<span style="color: #3d85c6;"><br>Weight Training</span> </h2>
<p>If HIIT burns more calories than regular cardio and helps to build muscle, then why bother with weight training?</p>
<p>For starters, HIIT can only be performed effectively or sustained for a short period of time, typically 4-30 minutes before you almost feel completely depleted of energy. Weight training can go on for an hour plus. Therefore, the muscle growth that you experience during a weight training session is far greater than in a HIIT session. In addition, weight training is highly metabolic and has far greater EPOC than both steady state cardio and HIIT put together.</p>
<p>Weight training is also essential in building strength, growing both your slow twitch and fast twitch muscle fibers, as well as helping you sculpt the physique that you desire. If this isn’t enough, here are some more incredible benefits of weight training:</p>
<ul>
<li>Improves posture and reduces posture associated pains</li>
<li>Improves your balance</li>
<li>Improves sleep, energy levels and overall mood</li>
<li>Promotes hormonal balance</li>
<li>Improves bone density and reduces risks of osteoporosis</li>
<li>Boosts metabolism and everyday fat burning</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;">The Bottom Line</span></h2>
<p>So, after reading all of this which form of training should you focus on?</p>
<p>Our honest opinion is all three. However, you must account for your schedule and whether you can consistently dedicate enough time to working out.</p>
<p>If you are short on time and your focus is fat loss, we strongly suggest HIIT training with a combination of weights added to your routine. We have hundreds of extremely effective weighted HIIT Routines.</p>
<p><a href="https://instagram.com/mrandmrsmuscle" target="_blank" title="MrandMrsMuscle HIIT Workouts - Preview" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click here to see the workouts</a></p>
<p>If increased muscle mass and muscle tone is your goal, you should focus on weight training, with a small amount of cardio added to the beginning and the end of your session.</p>
<p>If you are very new to training we recommend that you begin with steady state cardio such as incline walking, jogging, cycling or making use of the cross-trainer and shock your muscles with body weight exercises before progressing to HIIT and Weight Training.</p>
<p><em>Note: All of our workouts online can be done as multi-sets instead of HIIT.</em></p>
<p>Ultimately, your aim should be to move and expend as much calories as possible. It is important to note at this point that to reach your fitness goals you must combine exercise with a healthy eating regime specific to your lifestyle. If this is neglected, all your fat loss efforts will be in vain!</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>Want to stay updated with the latest in everything MrandMrsMuscle?</p>
<p><a href="https://instagram.com/mrandmrsmuscle" title="MrandMrsMuscle instagram">Follow us on Instagram</a></p>
<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script><ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display: block; text-align: center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4628548607785108" data-ad-slot="6535981438"></ins><script>// <![CDATA[
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/5-signs-you-may-be-deficient-in-potassium-and-limiting-muscle-growth</id>
    <published>2019-09-08T20:58:00+04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-08T21:39:08+04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/5-signs-you-may-be-deficient-in-potassium-and-limiting-muscle-growth"/>
    <title>5 Signs You May be DEFICIENT in Potassium and LIMITING Muscle Growth!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Addo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Potassium is an essential mineral that helps us to regulate your fluid balance, maintain healthy nerve function and stimulate smooth muscle contractions. Click <strong>Read More </strong>to find out what happens to your muscle gains if you do not get enough Potassium and how you can increase your levels naturally!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/5-signs-you-may-be-deficient-in-potassium-and-limiting-muscle-growth">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="spinach high in potassium" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0114/8164/5152/files/spinach_leaves_potassium_1024x1024.jpg?v=1567961550" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>As we continue to expand in the age of digital technology and social media we tend to seek instant gratification. For many of us, the need to be satisfied upon demand has affected the way that we choose, prepare and even eat our food. <br>Instead of spending time in the kitchen chopping fresh vegetables and cooking whole foods, we choose the pre-cut, ready-made and processed options. Rather than eating at home 5 nights out of 7, we choose fast food joints, restaurants or worse takeaways and eating them on the way home!<br><br>Granted, not everyone is like this. However, if you fall somewhere into this bracket the chances are you are lacking on many important nutrients that are vital to your health.</p>
<p>When we lack vital vitamins and minerals our bodies struggle to function at full capacity, leaving many of us falling short of reaching our fitness goals.<br>One mineral in particular that you may be struggling with is Potassium.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #0b5394;">What is Potassium?</span></h2>
<p>Potassium is an essential mineral that helps us to regulate your fluid balance, maintain healthy nerve function and stimulate smooth muscle contractions.<br>Generally speaking, a low-potassium diet rarely causes deficiency. However, with more and more foods being processed and filled with salts and additives (especially across Western style diets) many people are failing to hit their recommended daily intake (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23674806" target="_blank" title="Potassium and Health" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a>).</p>
<h2>
<br><span style="color: #3d85c6;">5 signs that you may have a potassium deficiency</span>
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Muscle Cramps or Spasms</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Potassium is found in your muscle cells and regulates muscular contractions by relaying signals from your brain to start and end movement. However, when your potassium levels are low your muscle contractions become delayed, causing muscle cramps.</p>
<p>Muscle cramps are involuntary contractions of one or more of your muscles that occur suddenly without warning. Low potassium can be triggered by excessive sweating, fluid loss or prolonged periods of exercise or intense activity.</p>
<p> </p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Fatigue</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Fatigue and feeling weak are early signs of potassium deficiency. This is because the low levels affect cellular processes, which in turn affects how our bodies secrete hormones and use nutrients from food. In addition, low levels of potassium can lead to low blood pressure, causing dizziness, fainting and overall weakness.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Poor Digestive Function: Bloating &amp; Constipation</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>As mentioned above, potassium is vital for smooth muscle contractions. The digestive system is made up of large muscles that need to contract smoothly to function optimally. Low potassium levels lead to weaker contractions, which slow down the movement of food throughout the digestive tract and causes bloating and constipation.</p>
<p> </p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Muscle Stiffness</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Muscle stiffness is usually an indication of rapid muscle breakdown and can sometimes be confused with DOMS (Delayed Onset of Muscle Soreness) which is a direct result of excessive/intense labour or exercise.</p>
<p>When potassium levels are very low, your blood vessels can become contracted for long periods of time and restrict blood flow to your muscles. The restricted blood flow means your cells receive less oxygen, which can cause them to rupture, resulting in stiffness.</p>
<p> </p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Mental Fatigue and Mood swings</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>As mentioned above, low levels of potassium disrupt nerve and cellular signals. A byproduct of this is a lack of optimal brain function, which causes mental fatigue and stress. In turn, this can affect your mood and leave you feeling happy one moment and disturbed the next.<br><br></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;">How to boost your Potassium?</span></h2>
<p><strong>DIET</strong></p>
<p>Eating foods rich in potassium is one of the best ways to increase your intake. Here are six foods that contain high levels:</p>
<ol>
<li>Greens (Spinach/Beet/Mustard Leaves)</li>
<li>Yams</li>
<li>White Beans</li>
<li>White Potatoes</li>
<li>Sweet Potatoes</li>
<li>Avocado</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>SUPPLEMENTS</strong></p>
<p>Obtaining your nutritional requirements from food is not always an option. If you suffer from allergies and intolerance or are simply time starved, ingesting vital minerals like potassium can prove to be a problem. This is where supplementation becomes a priority.</p>
<p>The most popular supplements to obtain potassium are:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Over-The-Counter Potassium Capsules</strong><br> However, these are limited by the FDA to containing just under 100milligrams of potassium which only makes up 2% of the recommended dietary intake for an Adult (currently 4,700mg).</li>
<li>
<strong>Electrolyte Powders<br> </strong>High quality electrolyte powders contain Sodium, Potassium, Calcium and Magnesium. This combination of minerals is imperative for complete muscle function, nerve communication as well as providing a consistent energy balance. Most of these minerals are lost through your sweat.</li>
<li>
<strong>Dipotassium Phosphate<br> </strong>Dipotassium Phosphate is a highly water-soluble salt. It is a great source of Potassium and easily assimilated into the body. It is best used with water or juice alongside training to fast replenish stores during intense exercise.</li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;">Bottom Line</span></h2>
<p>Ensuring that you meet your nutritional requirements can be a big challenge, especially if you have a busy schedule, fail to plan your meals or eat a lot of processed and fast foods.</p>
<p>Vitamins and minerals play such a vital role that becoming deficient in one area, tends to have a domino effect across other parts of the body. A body that cannot function optimally is one that cannot be in an ideal state of health.</p>
<p>However, it is very important to note that ingesting too many vitamins or minerals can also have a detrimental effect.</p>
<p>Studies show that too much potassium in the blood (known as Hyperkalemia) can be equally as bad. Too much can cause kidney failure, dehydration, tiredness, weakness, irregular heartbeats or palpitations and nausea (<a href="https://www.merckmanuals.com/home/hormonal-and-metabolic-disorders/electrolyte-balance/hyperkalemia-high-level-of-potassium-in-the-blood" target="_blank" title="Hyperkalemia (High Level of Potassium in the Blood)" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a>, <a href="https://www.webmd.com/a-to-z-guides/hyperkalemia-causes-symptoms-treatments#1" title="Hyperkalemia symptoms">3</a>).</p>
<p>So as with any diet it is important to make steady changes and account for how your body reacts.</p>
<br> <br> <script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4628548607785108" data-ad-slot="6535981438"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/why-you-should-do-hiit-for-weight-loss</id>
    <published>2019-09-07T17:09:00+04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-07T17:41:03+04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/why-you-should-do-hiit-for-weight-loss"/>
    <title>Why you should do HIIT for weight loss?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Addo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>HIIT workouts typically last from 4-30 minutes and provide the same benefits as continuous training and induce greater fat loss in a shorter time</span><span>. Click READ MORE to find out why you <strong>SHOULD</strong> be doing HIIT if you want to lose weight!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/blogs/blog/why-you-should-do-hiit-for-weight-loss">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Benefits of HIIT - MrandMrsMuscle" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0114/8164/5152/files/abs_29_aug_grande.png?v=1567862135" style="float: none;"></div>
<br>
<p>Today, HIIT is by far our favorite form of exercise but it wasn't always this way. In fact, we used to despise it! The shortness of breath, pounding heart rate, aching muscles and body temperature through the roof - it felt like torture.</p>
<p>So, what changed?</p>
<p>We did. HIIT took some getting used to, but we went from overweight, achy and lethargic to energized, strong and lean very quickly. </p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;"><strong>What is HIIT?</strong></span></h2>
<p>HIIT stands for High Intensity Interval Training and consists of short bursts of exercise at maximum intensity followed by low intensity rest periods. <br><br></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;">How long should you do HIIT?</span></h2>
<p>HIIT workouts typically last from 4-30 minutes and provide the same benefits as continuous training and induce greater fat loss in a shorter time (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28401638" title="The effects of high-intensity interval training vs. moderate-intensity continuous training on body composition in overweight and obese adults" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> , <a href="https://bjsm.bmj.com/content/53/10/655" title="Is interval training the magic bullet for fat loss?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a>). The reason HIIT is so effective in getting results is because the protocol forces you to workout at maximal capacity. Our maximal energy can only be high for a matter of seconds (typically 10-30 seconds). Once that time-frame passes our efforts diminish rapidly and the benefits are no longer the same.</p>
<p>The MrandMrsMuscle protocol is 30 seconds intense work and 10 seconds static or active rest. Our workouts are typically 10 minutes long and we only ever recommend going up to 20 minutes. With correct programming you can do HIIT safely up to 6x a week!</p>
<p><strong>Need help with your HIIT Program?</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://mrandmrsmuscle.com/collections/frontpage/" target="_blank" title="MrandMrsMuscle Workout Calendars" rel="noopener noreferrer">Use our Workout Calendars</a> <br><br></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d85c6;"><strong>What are the benefits of HIIT?</strong></span></h2>
<h4><span style="color: #000000;">1. Burn more calories in a short time</span></h4>
<p>This is one of the most obvious benefits of HIIT. <br>Today, we are living in a distracted and time poor society. Many of us are constantly on the go and struggling to balance lengthy work hours, family responsibilities and personal downtime. If, you fit into this category then you will be happy to know that research has shown <strong>HIIT to burn 20-30% more calories</strong> than most forms of exercise when done over the same length of time (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25162652" target="_blank" title="HIIT burns more calories in a short space of time" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a>).<br><br></p>
<p><strong>2. More responsive to Fat Loss</strong></p>
<p>All forms of exercise leads to fat loss, especially when paired with proper nutrition. However, studies show that HIIT invokes significant fat loss and results in lasting positive changes to cardio-metabolic markers such as resting HR, blood pressure and blood glucose (<a href="https://bjsm.bmj.com/content/51/6/494" target="_blank" title="Effects of high-intensity interval training on cardiometabolic health" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a>). <br><br></p>
<p><strong>3. Boost your Metabolism &amp; Oxygen consumption</strong></p>
<p>Your metabolism is a set of chemical reactions essential for life. These include converting food into energy, fueling proteins in our body and removing/excreting metabolic waste (CO2, Water, Nitrogenous compounds). When the metabolism slows down we are unable to function at optimal capacity and a by-product is rapid weight gain and lethargy.</p>
<p>HIIT pushes the body's metabolism towards using fat for energy instead of carbs and also increases our metabolic rate (the rate at which we burn calories) for several hours after exercise. Additionally, a study found that just 2-minutes of Sprint Intervals brought about the same amount of oxygen consumption as 30 minutes of continuous exercise in a 24 hour period (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22710610" target="_blank" title="Two minutes of sprint-interval exercise elicits 24-hr oxygen consumption similar to that of 30 min of continuous endurance exercise." rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a>).</p>
<p><br><strong>4. Increase Muscle Volume &amp; Muscle Definition</strong></p>
<p>During HIIT a significant amount of metabolic stress is placed on muscle tissue in a short space of time. This forces more micro-tears which results in increased volume and strength during recovery. In addition, the body responds with an increase in HGH (human growth hormone), IGF-1 (Insulin-like Growth Factor) and Testosterone to speed up the repair of damaged muscle proteins.</p>
<p><br><strong>5. HIIT is enjoyable and you are more likely to stick with it</strong></p>
<p>Your goals are dependent on consistency and consistency brings results!</p>
<p>Studies show that people find HIIT more enjoyable in comparison to steady-state exercise (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25486273" target="_blank" title="HIIT more enjoyable than Steady state exercise" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a>). The wide variety of exercise choice with HIIT (<a href="https://instagram.com/mrandmrsmuscle" target="_blank" title="1500 exercises - MrandMrsMuscle" rel="noopener noreferrer">we have over 1000 exercises on our IG page</a>) makes it a favorite among several people. However, this is also reliant on proper exercise programming/planning.</p>
<h2>
<br><span style="color: #3d85c6;">Bottom Line</span>
</h2>
<p>HIIT is one of the fastest and most enjoyable way to lose weight while improving your overall health. The intensity and pace is always set to the individual's ability and the workouts are extremely time efficient. However, we are also firm believers in pairing HIIT with active recovery days that involve low to moderate intensity exercise. If your ultimate goal is for muscle mass increase you should focus your efforts on traditional weight training.</p>
<br> <br><script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script><ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display: block; text-align: center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4628548607785108" data-ad-slot="6535981438"></ins><script>// <![CDATA[
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
